In the construction industry.
Growth.
Often requires diversification, which.
Introduces. Operational complexity,
and this also.
Applies.
To your marketing,
your marketing operations,
and how people interact with your brand.
It's a big.
Decision to bring in another service line.
So I wanted to talk about how people often
do this with their brands.
Do they keep it in the same website
under the same brand?
Do they do different websites with.
The same social media, same branding?
Or is it all completely separate?
And I think that's a really
personal decision based on your business
and your business goals.
So here we have
what most people are probably.
Doing in the US. Right?
Like custom home and renovation.
Put it under the same thing.
Maybe commercial is on there too.
Maybe it's
just a footer link or something like that.
All of your services are on this.
It's all about building
trust with your brand.
All your testimonials kind of.
Build this.
Momentum for your brand.
It helps with the trust.
It's harder to talk directly.
To the consumer when you're on a.
Website
that's. Just talking about what. You do.
If I offered. Marketing services.
Of all types to all people,
I would have to say, here's what I do.
Here are the things that I can do for you.
And I would have.
To put it. Up to the consumer
or the person on my.
Website to figure out.
How those things relate to their business.
But really, what I'm offering
is. Strategy.
Inside the construction industry.
So I can kind of.
Guess exactly.
The person
that's going to be on my website.
And I can say.
Here's how what I do applies to you.
So you end up talking about yourself
a lot more than the person
who's reading your website.
And it's. Difficult to talk directly.
To the consumer on your.
Website, but it still works like.
Here's a massive example of an extremely
successful national construction brand.
Kelly.
And they have tons of different services
on their one website.
So I mean, these are.
All a lot of like B2B services.
So maybe they have kind of one
general consumer.
That is.
Maybe shopping for multiple.
B2B services, or it's a.
Lot more about industry reputation
and trust for a brand than it is.
About. Speaking directly to a consumer.
So maybe that's coming into.
Play as to why they're.
All under one brand.
All of these things are extremely high
stakes.
they're all. Like, relationship
based purchases.
It's probably a long sales cycle.
So it makes sense that they have
all these things under one brand.
They're trying to build
a lot of reputation for this brand.
But this is a business
to consumer company.
They build.
New homes.
Ashton Woods and their.
Other Brand.
Is. Starlight Homes.
Ashton Woods. Is like.
Upper middle market homes.
So they're.
Immediately able.
To talk to the people, people who love.
Design, love our homes.
So they're immediately
talking to the person reading
or visiting their website.
And I bet their social media and,
All of
that stuff is able to talk to their.
Consumer a lot more closely.
And their other brand,
Starlight Homes. Is.
The first time homebuyer, brand.
So their entry level homes,
first time home buying is a menu item,
making home ownership more affordable.
This is exactly the value.
Proposition
that they have. For this. Exact person.
It will be a lot harder to do this
if they. Were under one brand.
It would be way more likely.
That they're like, yeah, we do great.
Design, but.
We also do affordability.
And they're talking about we and us.
But this is a much
this is a pretty huge company.
This is probably a bigger.
Company then range. Range line homes.
Like look at all
these places that they serve.
So massive company I'm sure they. Have.
The internal operational. Capacity.
For their marketing team
to operate multiple brands.
Multiple, style.
Guidelines, multiple brand voice
guidelines, you know, different personas.
That their.
Marketing teams understand.
So here is.
A company that's not as massive.
As. Starlight Homes or Ashton Woods.
But they also have multiple brands.
Diller Jones is kind of in
my neck of the woods.
their. Main core offering.
Is, Custom homes,
When I visit this website.
I can kind of. See, here
are the the. Regions.
I mean, this is a very regionally
constrained business.
Their other companies are Douma
Architecture and Travis.
Travis interior design.
when I'm looking.
For a custom builder, like I get to see.
Custom homes and menu items about custom
homes When I'm looking for an architect.
I get to see. Things. About architecture.
And when I'm looking for interior design,
I get to see things about interior design.
There are a lot of obvious. Reasons why.
This works so well.
But on the other hand, they need.
To have separate.
Brands.
They need to. Pay for separate. SEO.
They need to.
Pay for separate, Instagram.
Video. Creation.
It adds on to the cost of their marketing.
And these brands need to. Build trust.
In the marketplace on their own.
So what is. Your team's marketing. Skills?
What are your growth goals?
Do you have. A brand that you want to.
Build all the trust. In.
Or do you want to diversify.
Your brand and speak.
Closer to the. Consumer?
Ultimately,
there are a ton of personalized.
Factors.
That come into play when you're making
this decision, and it's very nuanced.
And then to add on to all.
Of it, AI. Is changing how.
SEO works.
So this used to be
a little bit easier of a decision.
If you're if you only have the money
to put into one good SEO campaign,
drive as much traffic.
To your website as you can.
But now with. AI.
People are spending more time on.
AI. Platforms, and social media. Is.
Constantly getting more people to spend
time on their platforms and figuring out.
How to, Limit
the amount of outbound links.
So you're we're.
All getting less.
Traffic to our websites All of these.
Factors come into play.
So that people are.
Spending more time on specific platforms
and less time on your.
Website.
So they're coming to your website
in more fragmented ways.
They might come in through one exact page
and then go straight to the contact form.
Because they've learned about your
website, developed a relationship with.
You on Instagram, and don't really.
Care to, learn more.
About your brand on your website.
They've already done all that.
So that.
Could be an argument
for having separate brands, having.
Separate websites for exact services.
Because if AI.
Is looking, you know,
what's the company to.
Go to that does.
High end luxury
custom homes in one exact region?
Is it a company that.
Does.
Everything, or is it a company
that's talking about this.
Specific. Region on their. Entire website?
This specific service?
And then when people. Get there,
you're. Talking.
Directly to them.
So the technological.
Changes are another factor that comes
into play, making it kind of difficult.
To take older advice at face.
Value.
And that just adds
another layer of nuance.
To this. Decision.
I hope that.
This thinking. Process has helped.
You understand how to grow
and build a better business.
Thanks for watching to the end.